

KAROLOS MELLATOS

FULL STACK ENGINEER

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Languages:

JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Python
Front-end Frameworks
React, Vue, Angular, Next, Nuxt, Gatsby

Node.js, Express, Nest.js, Net, Laravel, Django

Mobile App Frameworks

React Native, Flutter

Cloud Services:

AWS Amplify, AWS Lambda, Amazon DynamoDB, S3, AWS Cognito, EC2, Cloud Firestore, Firebase Realtime database, Firebase gateway

DevOps:

Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Docker, CI/CD, Webpack, Jest, Mocha, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall, TDD, SOLID, DRY

Engineering & Technology:

Software Engineering, Reverse Engineering, Artificial Intelligence

CONTACT DETAILS

Address

Flórina, Western Macedonia, Greece

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kmellatos

Email:

k.mellatos@gmail.com

EXECUTIVE PROFILE

I am a full-stack developer having more than 8 years of experience in building web and mobile applications. I'm a full stack, polyglot developer who is constantly learning how to make web/hybrid apps faster, leaner, and perfectly designed. I have worked on +30 CMS, CRM, Mobile, Analysis, Blockchain, eCommerce sites so far

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

FULL STACK ENGINEER

Self Employed | May 2021 - Present

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Heuro Labs GmbH | Sep 2019 - May 2021

- Developed headless CMS with React.js, Node.js, and Strapi
- Upgraded a powerful SaaS using Vue.js and Vuex, Vuetify framework
- Updated and added new RESTful APIs by using Apollo GraphQL + AWS Lambda function
- Improved search algorithm and architecture (+30% Big O)
- Implemented Aherf service for SEO and added JSON-LD for better search user experience.
- Increased CTR(Clickthrough rate) depends on A/B tests (+24% improved)
- Integrated payment gateway (stripe API) and localized by using i18n
- Transformed localStorage-based state management to Vuexbased system - Contributed to the in-browser slide generator and renderer using VueJS

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Eton Digital Ltd. | Jun 2018 - Aug 2019

- Improved a FinTech platform on the Frontend side and API implementation in React
- Developed mobile app from desktop web version with Firebase
- Added 30+ components to be used in the global app by using styled-components
- Redesigned global state management system with Redux thunk
- Simplified and improved UX from new design

- Improved performance by optimizing codes with modern JS and API handling
- Developed Admin panel with React and Node

MERN STACK DEVELOPER

Eton Digital Ltd. | Aug 2017 - Jun 2018

- Upgraded architecture of an enterprise clothing platform React, Node, MongoDB, Firebase (+7% improved in a number of requests per second)
- Developed headless CRM by using Strapi, Node, and React
- Redesigned database MySQL to MongoDB
- Developed price analysis platform depend on Price API and Google Merchant API with React and .Net
- Set up and administered a continuous integration system based on CruiseControl.NET, including nightly builds with unit tests run and delivery to the test servers.
- Switched to TeamCity for database scripts, versioning, and updating the system.
- Optimized the website's performance and planned for the web farm scaling: caching, using CDN, styles, and scripts bundling, and minification.
- Created and modified the database stored procedures, views, and functions.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Blockchain Terminal (BCT) | Oct 2015 - Feb 2017

- Acted as a Full Stack developer in a 30+ dev team for 2 years
- Improved UI/UX with React, Node, styled-components, d3.js, TradingView
- Developed and improved performance of +10 animation effects with custom styling
- Simplified global state management by using Mobx
- Suggested and Integrated real-time communication mechanism with Socket.IO and ws(npm package)

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Steficon Greece | Feb 2014 - Aug 2015

- Launched a Team Management CRM platform with jQuery, Node, Firebase, Salesforce and Twilio API
- Integrated Socket.IO for real-time team collaboration using NodeJS
- Developed chrome extension app for video conferencing by using WebRTC and Socket.IO

EDUCATION

ARISTOTLE UNIVERSITY OF THESSALONIKI (AUTH)

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science 2009 - 2013